Mpumelelo Hlongwane

ID: 8510016038085

Address: Unit 38, 10 Maldives Nossob Street, Winchester Hills, Johannesburg 2097

Phone: 073 441 0007

E-mail: mpumelelohlongwane@outlook.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mpumelelo-hlongwane-42b257145/

Objectives

I am blessed to possess an inquisitive and creative mindset which allows me to grasp new concepts promptly and to find unique solutions to everyday issues. I ran an informal product design and development business for more than 4 years, the main activity of the business was taking client needs, conceptualizing, designing and facilitating the manufacturing of a product that would meet these needs within their budget. This involved me analyzing the work that needed to be accomplished, breaking it down and designing a product and facilitating the project of manufacturing it.

This sharpened my critical and conceptual thinking skills, it developed an appreciation for a broad company structures and greatly enhanced my readiness to work within a team. It built in me an internal accountability for deadlines and accuracy.

After reaching the age I set earlier in my life I have reprioritized my career path by take an extended leave from my entrepreneurial pursuit to focus establishing myself in a reputable company and eventually enter and grow in the legal field.

Education

- Higher certificate in Project Management: Msimbi training (current)
- Bachelor of Law Degree: UNISA (Current)
- Higher certificate in Law: UNISA (2016)
- Certificate in Entrepreneurial development: Raymond Ackerman Academy for Entrepreneurial development/ University of Johannesburg(2014)
- Matric Institution: The National School of the Arts (2004)

Experience

Common Reporting Standards (CRS) Agent (Team leader's second in charge)(currently)

FNB - Retail & Commercial fulfilment

- · Work in various administrative and communications projects
- Presenting FNB products to clients
- Investigate clients complains with FATCA's foreign tax residency requirements
- · Contact clients that do not comply and take them through the process up to them being complaint
- Take on special investigations on general topics e.g. how particular campaigns are performing and why.
- As a second in charge I assume the team leaders duties in his absence which includes:
 - o Attending morning meetings with the department operations manager
 - Distribute work to the team everyday
 - o Keep record of team meetings

Managing Director (2011 –2017)

Msol innovations

- Conceptualized, designed and facilitated manufacturing new products
- Graphic design
- Sourced clients
- General business administration

• One of my products was selected for development by the Technology innovation agency's youth program. This consumed the bulk of the company's time from 2012 to 2014.

General worker (2010 –2011)

Phenomenal Properties (Company closed down)

- Office administration
- Contacting clients
- Typing out office documents e.g. rental mandates, contracts

•

Account Management Consultant (2008 –2010)

Standard Bank (People Serv: 086112 3444))

- Telephonically collect consumer debtor accounts in arrears
- Collecting accounts aged 30 to 60 days in arrears
- Negotiate, capture and follow up on payment arrangements
- Working towards and meeting predetermined collection targets

Skills

- Graphics Design: I have an extensive history in the arts and design
- Computer skills:
 - o Microsoft office
 - Including MS Projects
 - o I am a self-taught web developer hobbyist, Languages and Frameworks I can use:
 - Python: Intermediate to advance
 - > Django framework: intermediate to advanced
 - JavaScript: Intermediate
 - React
 - HTML and CSS
 - Bootstrap
 - MySQL
- Graphic Design software: Photoshop, illustrator, Dreamweaver

Product design and visualization software: Sketch up

Personality Profile

- · Very inquisitive, analytical, creative
- Enjoy understanding and interacting with people
- Hold respect as the highest priority
- A humble team player
- I am a fan of humor (at least 3 good belly laugh a week makes it all worth it)
- I am a fan of new information
- I am a fan of innovation
- Driven to succeed

References

• Phemelo Masilo

Position: Learning and development coordinator at FNB in the R & C fulfillment (CRS) department

Relationship: My mentor at FNB through my project management higher certificate

Contact: 065 871 1298

Clint Fynn

Position: Team leader at FNB in the R & C fulfillment (CRS) department

Relationship: My team leader

Contact: 076 955 1461

Nonhlanhla Heshu

Position: functional analyst at Wesbank in the ERP financial data warehouse

Relationship: I was part of her Python classes at Wesbank

Contact: 081 499 3848